My job at Twitter
عملي في تويتر
is to ensure user trust,
هو ضمان ثقة المستخدم
protect user rights and keep users safe,
حماية حقوق المستخدم والحفاظ على أمان المستخدمين
both from each other
من بعضهم البعض
and, at times, from themselves.
وفي بعض الأحيان، من أنفسهم
Let's talk about what scale looks like at Twitter.
دعونا نتحدّث عما يبدو عليه حجم تويتر.
Back in January 2009,
في يناير 2009،
we saw more than two million new tweets each day
شاهدنا أكثر من مليوني تغريدة كلّ يوم
on the platform.
على الموقع.
January 2014, more than 500 million.
في يناير 2014, أكثر من 500 مليون.
We were seeing two million tweets
كنّا نرى مليوني تغريدة
in less than six minutes.
في أقل من ستة دقائق.
That's a 24,900-percent increase.
هذا يعادل زيادةً بنسبة %24,900
Now, the vast majority of activity on Twitter
الآن,، الأغلبيّة العظمى من النشاطات على تويتر
puts no one in harm's way.
لا تسبب أذىً لأحد.
There's no risk involved.
ليس فيها أي خطر.
My job is to root out and prevent activity that might.
وظيفتي هي أن أمنع وأقتلع أي نشاط قد يكون خطِراً.
Sounds straightforward, right?
يبدو أمراً واضحاً، صح؟
You might even think it'd be easy,
وقد تظنون أنّه قد يكون سهلاً.
given that I just said the vast majority
خصوصاً وأني قلت للتو أن الأغلبيّة العظمى
of activity on Twitter puts no one in harm's way.
من النشاط على تويتر لا تؤذي أحداً.
Why spend so much time
لماذا نضيّع الكثيرمن الوقت
searching for potential calamities
باحثين عن مصائب محتملة
in innocuous activities?
في نشاطات غير مؤذية؟
Given the scale that Twitter is at,
نظراً إلى حجم تويتر حاليّاً
a one-in-a-million chance happens
فإن احتمال حدوث الواحد في المليون
500 times a day.
هو 500 مرة يوميّاً
It's the same for other companies
ينطبق ذلك على الشركات الأخرى
dealing at this sort of scale.
التي تتعامل مع أحجام مماثلة.
For us, edge cases,
بالنسةِ لنا، الحالات الهامشيّة
those rare situations that are unlikely to occur,
هذه الحالات النادرة الغير محتملة الحدوث،
are more like norms.
تحدث بشكل اعتيادي.
Say 99.999 percent of tweets
لنفترض أن 99,999% من التغاريد
pose no risk to anyone.
لا تمثّل خطراً على أحد.
There's no threat involved.
ليس فيها أي تهديد.
Maybe people are documenting travel landmarks
ربما أُناس يوثقون معالم رحلة
like Australia's Heart Reef,
إلى الشعاب المرجانيّة الأُستراليّة،
or tweeting about a concert they're attending,
أو يغردون عن حفلةٍ حضروها،
or sharing pictures of cute baby animals.
أو يتبادلون صور أطفال حيوانات ظريفة.
After you take out that 99.999 percent,
بعد أن تستبعد هذه ال99,999%
that tiny percentage of tweets remaining
فإن النسبة الضئيلة المتبقية
works out to roughly
تساوي بشكل تقريبي
150,000 per month.
150,000 شهريّاً.
The sheer scale of what we're dealing with
الحجم الهائل الذي نتعامل معه
makes for a challenge.
يشكل تحدّياً
You know what else makes my role
أتعلمون بالإضافة لذلك ما يجعل دوري
particularly challenging?
تحدياً من نوع خاص؟
People do weird things.
البشر يقومون بأعمال عجيبة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I have to figure out what they're doing,
ويتوجّب عليَّ أن أفهم ما يفعلون،
why, and whether or not there's risk involved,
ولماذا، وهل هناك مخاطرة في الموضوع،
often without much in terms of context
في أغلب الأحيان بدون معرفة السياق
or background.
أو الخلفيّة.
I'm going to show you some examples
سأعرض لكم بعض الأمثلة
that I've run into during my time at Twitter --
التي صادفتها أثناء عملي في تويتر
these are all real examples —
-هذه أمثلة من الواقع-
of situations that at first seemed cut and dried,
من حالات بدت للوهلة الأولى واضحة ومباشرة
but the truth of the matter was something
لكنها في حقيقة الأمر كانت
altogether different.
شيئاً مختلفاً كليّاً.
The details have been changed
تمّ تغيير التفاصيل
to protect the innocent
لحماية الأبرياء
and sometimes the guilty.
وأحياناً المذنبين.
We'll start off easy.
لنبدأ بمثال سهل.
["Yo bitch"]
["يا،كلبة."]
If you saw a Tweet that only said this,
إذا رأيت تغريدة تقول هذا
you might think to yourself,
قد تظن في نفسك،
"That looks like abuse."
"هذا يبدو كإساءة."
After all, why would you want to receive the message,
في النهاية، لماذا سترغب أن تصلك رسالة،
"Yo, bitch."
"يا،كلبة."
Now, I try to stay relatively hip
الآن، أحاول أن أتابع الموضة
to the latest trends and memes,
بكل مافيها من موديلات وصيحات،
so I knew that "yo, bitch"
ولذا أعرف أن "يا، كلبة"
was also often a common greeting between friends,
هي تحيّة شائعة بين الأصدقاء،
as well as being a popular "Breaking Bad" reference.
إضافة لكونها استعارة متداولة من مسلسل "بريكنغ باد".
I will admit that I did not expect
سأعترف أني لم أتوقّع
to encounter a fourth use case.
أن أصادف استخداماً رابعاً.
It turns out it is also used on Twitter
يظهر أنّها تستخدم على تويتر
when people are role-playing as dogs.
عندما يلعب الناس دور الكلاب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And in fact, in that case,
في الواقع، في هذه الحالة،
it's not only not abusive,
فإنها ليست فقط غير مؤذية،
it's technically just an accurate greeting.
إنها تقنياً التحيّة الصحيحة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So okay, determining whether or not
حسناً، أن نقرر ما إذا
something is abusive without context,
كان شيءٌ مؤذياً بدون معرفة السياق
definitely hard.
هو أمر صعب حتماً.
Let's look at spam.
لننظر إلى البريد المزعج.
Here's an example of an account engaged
هذا مثال على حساب متورط
in classic spammer behavior,
بسلوك إزعاج تقليدي،
sending the exact same message
يرسل الرسالة ذاتها
to thousands of people.
إلى آلاف الناس.
While this is a mockup I put together using my account,
على الرغم من أن هذا نموذج جمعته مستخدمةً حسابي،
we see accounts doing this all the time.
إلّا أننا نرى حسابات تفعل ذلك كل الوقت.
Seems pretty straightforward.
يبدو قراراً واضحاً
We should just automatically suspend accounts
علينا تلقائيّاً أن نفصل الحسابات
engaging in this kind of behavior.
المتورطة بمثل هذا التصرّف.
Turns out there's some exceptions to that rule.
يظهر أن هناك استثناءات لهذه القاعدة.
Turns out that that message could also be a notification
يظهر أن تلك الرسالة قد تكون اشعاراً
you signed up for that the International Space Station is passing overhead
طلبته أنت لتعرف أن محطة الفضاء الدولية تحلّق من فوقك
because you wanted to go outside
لأنك تريد الذهاب للخارج
and see if you could see it.
لترى إن كنت تستطيع مشاهدتها.
You're not going to get that chance
لن تحصل على تلك الفرصة
if we mistakenly suspend the account
إذا قمنا بفصل هذا الحساب بالخطأ
thinking it's spam.
معتقدين أنه إزعاج.
Okay. Let's make the stakes higher.
حسناً. لنرفع مستوى المخاطرة.
Back to my account,
عودةً إلى حسابي،
again exhibiting classic behavior.
مرّة أخرى يظهر تصرّفاً تقليديداً
This time it's sending the same message and link.
لكن هذه المرة يرسل الرسالة مع وصلة.
This is often indicative of something called phishing,
هذا غالباً يدل على شيء يسمى التصيُّد،
somebody trying to steal another person's account information
شخص يحاول سرقة معلومات حساب شخص آخر
by directing them to another website.
عن طريق توجيههم إلى موقع آخر
That's pretty clearly not a good thing.
من الواضح جداً أنه ليس شيئاً حسناً
We want to, and do, suspend accounts
نحن نريد أن، وبالفعل نقوم بفصل الحسابات
engaging in that kind of behavior.
المتورطة بمثل هذه التصرفات
So why are the stakes higher for this?
إذن لماذا مستوى الخطر أعلى هنا؟
Well, this could also be a bystander at a rally
حسناً، قد يكون هذا متفرِّجا في مظاهرة
who managed to record a video
تمكن من تسجيل فيديو
of a police officer beating a non-violent protester
لضابط شرطة يضرب متظاهراً مسالماً
who's trying to let the world know what's happening.
ويريد أن يُري العالم ما يحصل.
We don't want to gamble
لا نريد أن نقامر
on potentially silencing that crucial speech
على احتمال إسكات الإعلام المهم
by classifying it as spam and suspending it.
بتصنيفه كإزعاج وتعليقه.
That means we evaluate hundreds of parameters
هذا يعني أنه علينا تقييم المئات من المتغيرات
when looking at account behaviors,
عند النظر في سلوكيات الحساب،
and even then, we can still get it wrong
ومع ذلك، قد نرتكب الأخطاء
and have to reevaluate.
ونضطر لإعادة التقييم.
Now, given the sorts of challenges I'm up against,
الآن، بالنظر إلى نوعيّة التحدي الذي يواجهني،
it's crucial that I not only predict
من الجوهري ليس فقط أن أتنبأ
but also design protections for the unexpected.
بل أيضاً ان أُصمم دفاعات لغير المتوقع.
And that's not just an issue for me,
وهذا ليس شـأناً يهمني فقط،
or for Twitter, it's an issue for you.
أو يهم تويتر، إنّه شأنكم أيضاً.
It's an issue for anybody who's building or creating
إنّه أمر يهمُّ أي شخص يبني أو يبدع
something that you think is going to be amazing
شيئاً قد تظنه سيصبح رائعاً
and will let people do awesome things.
وسيمكّن الناس من عمل أشياءَ عظيمة.
So what do I do?
إذن ماذا أفعل؟
I pause and I think,
أتوقف وأُفكر،
how could all of this
كيف يمكن لكل هذا
go horribly wrong?
أن يؤدّي لخطأ فادح؟
I visualize catastrophe.
أتخيّل الكارثة.
And that's hard. There's a sort of
وذلك صعب، هناك نوع من
inherent cognitive dissonance in doing that,
الصراع الداخلي المتأصل في القيام بذلك،
like when you're writing your wedding vows
كأنك تكتب وعود الزواج
at the same time as your prenuptial agreement.
في نفس الوقت الذي تكتب فيه اتفاقيّة ما قبل الزواج.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But you still have to do it,
ولكن يتوجّب عليك فعل ذلك،
particularly if you're marrying 500 million tweets per day.
خصوصاً إذا كنت ستتزوّج 500 تغريدة في اليوم.
What do I mean by "visualize catastrophe?"
ماذا أعني بتخيّل الكارثة؟
I try to think of how something as
أحاول أن أفكر كيف يمكن
benign and innocuous as a picture of a cat
لشيء حميد وغير ضار كصورة قطّة
could lead to death,
أن يؤدي للموت،
and what to do to prevent that.
وما يمكن فعله لمنع ذلك.
Which happens to be my next example.
وهذا هو المثال التالي.
This is my cat, Eli.
هذه هي قطتي، أيلي.
We wanted to give users the ability
أردنا أن نعطي المستخدمين القدرة
to add photos to their tweets.
على إضافة الصور في تغاريدهم.
A picture is worth a thousand words.
الصورة تساوي ألف كلمة.
You only get 140 characters.
يسمح لك فقط ب140 حرف.
You add a photo to your tweet,
تضيف صورةً إلى تغريدتك،
look at how much more content you've got now.
أنظر كم زاد المحتوى لديك الآن.
There's all sorts of great things you can do
هناك الكثير من الأمور الرائعة بإمكانك القيام بها
by adding a photo to a tweet.
عند إضافة صورة إلى تغريدة.
My job isn't to think of those.
وظيفتي ليست التفكير في ذلك.
It's to think of what could go wrong.
إنما التفكير فيما قد يحصل بالخطأ.
How could this picture
كيف يمكن لهذه الصورة
lead to my death?
أن تتسبب في موتي؟
Well, here's one possibility.
حسناً، إليكم هذا الاحتمال.
There's more in that picture than just a cat.
في هذه الصورة هناك أكثر من مجرّد قطّة.
There's geodata.
هناك معلومات جغرافيّة.
When you take a picture with your smartphone
عندما تلتقط صورة بهاتفك الذكي
or digital camera,
أو كاميرتك الرقميّة،
there's a lot of additional information
هناك الكثير من المعلومات الإضافيّة
saved along in that image.
مخزنة في تلك الصورة.
In fact, this image also contains
في الحقيقة، هذه الصورة تحتوي أيضاً
the equivalent of this,
ما يعادل هذا،
more specifically, this.
وبالتحديد، هذا.
Sure, it's not likely that someone's going to try
بالتاكيد، ليس من المتوقع أنّ شخصاً سيحاول
to track me down and do me harm
ملاحقتي والتسبب بأذيّتي
based upon image data associated
اعتماداً على معلومات مرتبطة
with a picture I took of my cat,
بصورة التقطها لقطتي،
but I start by assuming the worst will happen.
لكنني ابدأ بافتراض أن الأسوأ سيحصل.
That's why, when we launched photos on Twitter,
ولهذا السبب، عندما أطلقنا الصور في تويتر،
we made the decision to strip that geodata out.
قررنا أن نستثني المعلومات الجغرافيّة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
If I start by assuming the worst
إذا بدأت بافتراض الاسوأ
and work backwards,
ثم العمل رجوعاً،
I can make sure that the protections we build
يصبح بإمكاني التأكّد من أن الدفاعات التي نبنيها
work for both expected
فعّالة لكل من المتوقع
and unexpected use cases.
وغير المتوقع من المستخدمين.
Given that I spend my days and nights
وحيث أنني أقضي نهاري وليلي
imagining the worst that could happen,
في تخيّل أسوأ ما قد يحدث،
it wouldn't be surprising if my worldview was gloomy.
فليس من الغريب أن تكون نظرتي للعالم سوداويّة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's not.
ليست كذلك.
The vast majority of interactions I see --
الغالبيّة العظمى من التفاعلات التي أراها
and I see a lot, believe me -- are positive,
-وأرى الكثير، صدقوني- هي إيجابيّة،
people reaching out to help
أناس يسعون للمساعدة
or to connect or share information with each other.
أو التواصل أو مشاركة المعلومات مع بعضهم البعض.
It's just that for those of us dealing with scale,
إلّا أنه بالنسبة لمن يتعامل مع حجم كبير،
for those of us tasked with keeping people safe,
ومن يتحملون مهمّة حماية الناس،
we have to assume the worst will happen,
يتحتم علينا افتراض أن الأسوأ سيحدث،
because for us, a one-in-a-million chance
لأنّه بالنسبة لنا، احتمال الواحد في المليون
is pretty good odds.
هو احتمال جيّد جدّاً.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)